<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Cinephile</title>
    <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Cinephile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:26:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Touch of Evil (1958)</title>
      <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/10h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:26:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/10h/</guid>
      <description>Touch of Evil (1958) Director: Orson Welles The behind-the-scenes palace intrigue of Touch of Evil constitutes enough dramatic tension to stand as a Welles picture. The 1958 project was theoretically too low-brow for Welles, as he initially &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kiss Me Deadly (1955)</title>
      <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/9h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:26:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/9h/</guid>
      <description>Kiss Me Deadly (1955) Director: Robert Aldrich In conclusion, Kiss Me Deadly is a captivating and groundbreaking film that has left a lasting impact on the world of cinema. Its unique narrative style, intense performances, and thought-provoking themes make it a must-watch for any movie enthusiast. From its intriguing plot to its mesmerizing cinematography, this film continues to captivate &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pickup on South Street (1953)</title>
      <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/8h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:26:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/8h/</guid>
      <description>Pickup on South Street (1953) Director: Samuel Fuller Pickup on South Street is a 1953 Cold War spy film noir written and directed by Samuel Fuller. The film stars Richard Widmark, Jean Peters, and Thelma Ritter&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In a Lonely Place (1950)</title>
      <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/7h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:26:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/7h/</guid>
      <description>In a Lonely Place (1950) Director: Nicholas Ray Rebel Without A Cause and Bigger Than Life each explored the dark, seedy underbelly of the white picket fence American dream while 1950&amp;rsquo;s In a Lonely Place explores, with Ray&amp;rsquo;s trademark combination of steely toughness and sensitivity, a man of dark impulses and explosive violence fighting a war on two fronts against a heartless Hollywood &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reckelss Moment (1949)</title>
      <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/6h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:26:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/6h/</guid>
      <description>The Reckless Moment (1949) Director: Max Ophuls The Reckless Moment is a 1949 American film noir melodrama directed by Max Ophüls, produced by Walter Wanger, and released by Columbia Pictures with Burnett &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of the Past (1947)</title>
      <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/5h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:26:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/5h/</guid>
      <description>Out of the Past (1947) Director: Jacques Tourneur Jacques Tourneur&amp;rsquo;s Out of the Past is one of the greatest of the genre, unsparing and bleakly beautiful. Robert Mitchum&amp;rsquo;s Jeff Markham is the ex-private eye looking to bury his shady past in a &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gilda (1946)</title>
      <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/4h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:26:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/4h/</guid>
      <description>Gilda (1946) Director: Charles Vidor Gilda is a 1946 American film noir directed by Charles Vidor and starring Rita Hayworth in her signature role and Glenn Ford. The film is known for cinematographer Rudolph Maté&amp;rsquo;s lush photography, costume designer Jean Louis&amp;rsquo;s wardrobe for Hayworth (particularly for the dance numbers), and choreographer Jack Cole&amp;rsquo;s staging of &amp;ldquo;Put the Blame on Mame&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Amado Mio&amp;rdquo;, sung by Anita Ellis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Big Sleep (1946)</title>
      <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/3h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:26:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/3h/</guid>
      <description>The Big Sleep (1946) Director: Howard Hawks The Big Sleep, American film noir, released in 1946, that was based on Raymond Chandler&amp;rsquo;s classic 1939 novel of the same name. It was directed by Howard Hawks, cowritten by author William Faulkner, and starred the popular team of Humphrey Bogart and Lauren Bacall.Although its plot is often cited as one of the most baffling in film history, The Big Sleep was deemed culturally significant by &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laura (1944)</title>
      <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/2h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:25:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/2h/</guid>
      <description>Laura (1944) Director: Otto Preminger historynerd9292 • 4 mo. ago. Laura is one of my favorite movies—well-acted, well-paced, great ending, stunning score, fluid cinematography. Clifton Webb should&amp;rsquo;ve won the best supporting actor Oscar for his performance, as he was nominated, which was his first movie role. &amp;ldquo;Laura&amp;rdquo; remains one of the top noirs because Preminger fought &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Indemnity (1944)</title>
      <link>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/1h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:24:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://restinsleep.github.io/pages/1h/</guid>
      <description>Double Indemnity (1944) Director: Billy Wilder Double Indemnity is one of the foundational pillars of the film noir genre, a term originally applied by French critic Nino Frank to American thriller or detective films in the period 1944-54, generally characterized by dark lighting, a crime, and a moral lesson (&amp;ldquo;Film Noir - Everything You Need to Know&amp;rdquo;). When Double Indemnity was released &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
